Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES III. Publications, 1930-80
Sophia Smith Collection
Planned Parenthood Federation of America Records (PPFA II): SERIES III. Publications
1930-80
Planned Parenthood Federation of America
371a_s3
15 linear feet
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
This series consists of the alphabetical (classified) files kept of the PPFA office, much of it published materials covering a variety of topics such as abortion, population, contraceptives, marriage counseling, and poverty as it relates to population. There are legal briefs, bibliographies, and catalogs as well as articles, pamphlets, and books. This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
The bulk of this series is arranged alphabetically by title. Much of this material is published by PPFA and written by its staff. Many items are reprints from a variety of journals and newspapers. Some are miscellaneous reprints or are written by outside organizations and authors. The publications cover a variety of topics of interest to PPFA, such as abortion, population, contraceptives, marriage counseling, and poverty as it relates to population. There are legal briefs, bibliographies, and catalogs as well as articles, pamphlets, and books. Two boxes at the end are arranged alphabetically by author, and one box has no discernible order.
NOTE: To view the series descriptions and contents lists, click on the series links below. Some files are quite large and may take several minutes to load, depending on your internet connection.
This collection is organized into ten series:
I. Chronological Files
II. Classified Files
Part 1
Part 2
III. Publications
IV. Subject Files
V. Affiliates
Part 1
Part 2
VI. Regions
VII. Minutes
VIII. Foreign
IX. Guttmacher
[SERIES X. Restricted]
PPFA has closed records created January 1, 1985 or later, with the exception of many published materials which are open to research. All records having to do with clinic defense and security are closed. PPFA has closed a small section of files in box 206 for fifty years. Researchers may request access to restricted materials from PPFA.
The Margaret Sanger Papers Microfilm Edition: Smith College Collection Series, edited by Esther Katz, et al., University Publications of America, 1995
Periodic additions to the collection are expected.
PPFA deposited these records in 1988. Various departments have since sent miscellaneous additions.
Best, Winfield; Guttmacher, Alan Frank, 1898-; McCormick, Katherine Dexter, 1876-1967; Rose, D. Kenneth; Sanger, Margaret, 1879-1966; Wattleton, Faye; Alan Guttmacher Institute--History; American Birth Control League--History; Abortion--Law and legislation-United States--History--Sources; Abortion services--History--Sources; Birth Control Clinical Research Bureau (New York, N.Y.)--History; Birth Control Federation of America--History; International Planned Parenthood Federation--History; Planned Parenthood Federation of America--History; Planned Parenthood-World Population (U.S.)--History; Birth control clinics--United States--History--Sources; Birth control--History--20th century--Sources; Birth control--Developing countries--History--20th century--Sources; Contraceptives--Research--History; Hygiene, Sexual--History--20th century; Human reproduction--Political aspects; Population policy--History--20th century; Reproductive health--Statistics; Sex instruction--History; Women--Health and hygiene--United States--20th century; Women's health services--United States--20th century
This Series forms part of the PPFA II Records
See also the PPFA I Records.
Related material can be found in the Margaret Sanger Papers, Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College, and at the Library of Congess.
- SERIES III. PUBLICATIONS
  - Pamphlets, miscellaneous, undated (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - "ABC's of Birth Control," 1969 (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - "The ABC of Planned Parenthood," Campaign Pamphlet 1948 (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - "Abortion, Birth Control and the Ethics of Limiting Reproduction," Declaration of the Religious Affairs Committee 1972 (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - "About Abortion," 1970 (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - "Abortion: Can We Lose Our Right to Choose?" Bea Blair, Reprint, Ms. Magazine, Oct. 1973 (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Abortion, Chicago, New York, Population, Fertility, Indianapolis 1942 (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - "The Abortion Decision: Two Years Later," Reprinted from Commonweal, 2/14/75 (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - "Abortions on Medicaid? The Bartlett Amendment," Reprint from Commonweal, May 9, 1975 (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - "About Birth Control," 1938-1941? (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Academy of Medicine report, "How P.P. Services have Carried Out Recommendations of," undated (Box 91, Folder 11)
  - "Acceptance of An Oral Contraceptive Program in a Large Metropolitan Area," Reprint, Amer. Jnl Obstetrics and Gyn. 1965 (Box 91, Folder 12)
  - "Additional Statements by President Johnson Concerning Population," 3/66 (Box 91, Folder 13)
  - "Adolescent Sexual Behavior," By Mary S. Calderone, M.D., P.T.A. Magazine, Sept. 1964 (Box 91, Folder 14)
  - Ads for Books and Pamphlets 1934-1949 (Box 91, Folder 15)
  - "Advanced Hygiene Protects Womanpower," By Buckman, Film, Reprint, Modern Industry 1944 (Box 91, Folder 16)
  - Advances in Planned Parenthood, Proceedings of Annual Meetings AAPPP, 4/64, Dallas, Texas, Sobrero and Lewitt, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 17)
  - Affiliates: Family Planning Program in the War Against Poverty 1966 (Box 91, Folder 18)
  - "Alcohol and Drug Abuse Among Women in Child Bearing Years," L.V. Hall and D.F. Wright, Reprint 1978 (Box 91, Folder 19)
  - "American Businessmen Speak Out on the [?]," Reprint, Wall Street Journal, 2/18/65 (Box 91, Folder 20)
  - A Human Right, Family Planning Policy Statements, 9/68 (Box 91, Folder 21)
  - "AMA Revises Policy on Population Control," Reprint, JAMA, Dec. 21, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 22)
  - American Medical Association, Journal of..., Reprint, "Population Growth", July 8, 1961 (Box 91, Folder 23)
  - "America's Population Crisis," By Dr. Philip Hauser, from Look, Nov. 1961 (Box 91, Folder 24)
  - Pamphlets, Foreign Language, undated (Box 91, Folder 25)
  - Aid for International Development, A Report, "People and Growth," Department of State 1961-1962 (Box 91, Folder 26)
  - Aims of Birth Control, ("Review of Recent Progress"), Nicholson J. Eastman, M.D. 1942 (Box 91, Folder 27)
  - "Alabama's Program," By J.N. Baker, M.D. 1941 (Box 91, Folder 28)
  - American Academy of Pediatrics, "Text of Policy Statement on Family Planning," Approved Oct. 20, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 29)
  - Manual of Standard Practice, (American Birth Control League) 1938 (Box 91, Folder 30)
  - "The American Birth Control League, Its Aims and Program," undated (Box 91, Folder 31)
  - "American Fertility Cult, Our Irresponsible Birthrate," Columbia University Forum, Summer 1960 (Box 91, Folder 32)
  - American Jewish Congress, Statement on Birth Control by the Governing Council, Nov. 7, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 33)
  - American Journal of Nursing, Reprint, "Counseling for Family Planning," By Miriam Manisoff, 12/66 (Box 91, Folder 34)
  - American Medical Association, Reprint, Journal AMA, May 30, 1936 (Box 91, Folder 35)
  - "American Medicine Accepts Birth Control," 1937 (Box 91, Folder 36)
  - "American Population Growth and Prosperity," Adolph Schmidt and L. du P. Copeland, A Meeting 1962 (Box 91, Folder 37)
  - "The American People Support P.P.," undated (Box 91, Folder 38)
  - "America's 'Amazing Women'," By Clarence W. Hall, Reader's Digest Article, July 1955 (Box 91, Folder 39)
  - An Appeal for Action, Statement By Members of Planning Commission on Negro Problems, Nat'l Advisory Council, Negro Problems, undated (Box 91, Folder 40)
  - "An Integrated Fertility Service," Abraham Stone, Frances E. Shields 1955 (Box 91, Folder 41)
  - "Record A Statement," By Samuel W. Anderson, undated, [MISSING] (Box 91)
  - Anatomy of a Victory, Panel Discussion on a Public Controversy 1959 (Box 91, Folder 42)
  - "An Inventory of Contraceptive Methods Adapted to Public Health Practice," by Dr. M.S. Calderone, Reprint, AJPH, 10/62 (Box 91, Folder 43)
  - Annual Meeting Makes News Across the Nation 1945 (Box 91, Folder 44)
  - "Are Smaller Families Coming Back in Style?" By Winfield Best, Reprint, Parents Magazine, Nov. 1964 (Box 91, Folder 45)
  - "Are Too Many Babies Being Born?" by Dr. Wm. Vogt, Sat. Eve. Post, Rep. 1962 (Box 91, Folder 46)
  - "Are We Afraid of Birth Control?" Paul L. Jones, Reprint, Pittsburgh Courier, also listed, "What is P.P.," undated (Box 91, Folder 47)
  - "Are We Overworking the Stork?" By Clarence Senior, Reprint, Parents' Magazine 1961 (Box 91, Folder 48)
  - "Are you Planning to be Married?," 1963 (Box 91, Folder 49)
  - "As a Taxpayer," Campaign Leaflet 1950, undated (Box 91, Folder 50)
  - "As Important as Your Belief in a Strong Nation," undated (Box 91, Folder 51)
  - Asia 1953 (Box 91, Folder 52)
  - "Ask Your Physician," Reprint, Woman's Home Companion 1938 (Box 91, Folder 53)
  - "Asking the Folks About Birth Control," Reprint, Essence, September 1972 (Box 91, Folder 54)
  - "Assessment of Reproductive Risk in Nonpregnant Women," By Gordon W. Perkin, M.D., Bangkok, Thailand 1968 (Box 91, Folder 55)
  - "Assistance for the Sexually Active Female," By Takey Crist, M.D., Reprint, The Youth and Student Affairs 1973 (Box 91, Folder 56)
  - Avalanche of Children, Hunger Lurks, Spanish, "Alud de ninos, el hambre achecha," Vision Magazine 1964 (Box 91, Folder 57)
  - "Baby Boom, The," Prepared by The Dickinson Research Memorial, Sept. 1955 (Box 91, Folder 58)
  - Babies, 100,000,000, undated (Box 91, Folder 59)
  - "Babies Mean Better Business," 1949 Campaign, undated (Box 91, Folder 60)
  - Literature, "Babies Should Be Planned" 1957 (Box 91, Folder 61)
  - "Balancing Population and Resources," Max Adams, Reprint, Journal of Heredity 1952 (Box 91, Folder 62)
  - "Basal Temperature Charts," undated (Box 91, Folder 63)
  - "Basics of Birth Control," 1977 (Box 91, Folder 64)
  - Basics of Birth Control 1972 (Box 91, Folder 65)
  - "Before Young People Marry," Abraham Stone, M.D., Readers Digest, 9/55 (Box 91, Folder 66)
  - "Better Care for Mother and Child," Children's Bureau 1936 (Box 91, Folder 67)
  - "Better Health for 13,000,000" Negro Literature, 1943 (Box 91, Folder 68)
  - "Betty and Jack Talk About Government Birth Control," PA Catholic Conference, Harrisburg, undated (Box 91, Folder 69)
  - "Biological and Medical Aspects of Contraception," Sanger, 1934, Papers Presented at Washington Confernce, 1/34 (Box 91, Folder 70)
  - "Birth Control," By Winfield Best and Louis Dupré, Reprint, Encyclopedia Britannica 1967 (Box 91, Folder 71)
  - "Birth Control: Academy Report Stresses Burdens High Birth Rate," Reprint, Science 1965 (Box 91, Folder 72)
  - "Birth Control, A Choice: Genocide or Survival?," By Frances E. Ruffin, Reprint, Essence, September 1972 (Box 91, Folder 73)
  - "Birth Control and the Negro Woman," By Mary Smith, Reprint, Ebony Magazine 1968 (Box 91, Folder 74)
  - "Birth Control and a New Birth of Freedom," By Harriet Pilpel, Reprint, Ohio State Law Journal 1966 (Box 91, Folder 75)
  - "Birth Control and the Poor," Reprinted from Look Magazine, April 7, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 76)
  - "Birth Control: Businessmen Back It," Reprinted from Business Week, 5/15/65 (Box 91, Folder 77)
  - "Birth Control in Comprehensive Health Care," Reprint, JAMA, June 20,1966 (Box 91, Folder 78)
  - Birth Control: Complete Book of, By Alan F. Guttmacher, M.D. 1961 (Box 91, Folder 79)
  - Birth Control: "Court Bars Connecticut Curbs," June 7, 1965 (Box 91, Folder 80)
  - Birth Control: "Eased Birth Curb Reported Backed in Vatican Panel," Reprint, N.Y. Times, June 23, 1966 (Box 91, Folder 81)
  - "Birth Control Issue," By Carl T. Rowan 1971 (Box 91, Folder 82)
  - "Birth Control: The Pill and the Church," John Rock, Gynecologist, Newsweek Reprint, July 6, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 83)
  - "Birth Control as a Public Health Measure," By C.E.A. Winslow 1938 (Box 91, Folder 84)
  - "Birth Control and Public Policy," Fund Raising, Pamphlet 1960 (Box 91, Folder 85)
  - "Birth Control and Public Responsibility," Arnold Maremont, A Meeting 1963 (Box 91, Folder 86)
  - Birth Control (Under Foreign Aid), Funds, reprints July, 1963 (Box 91, Folder 87)
  - "Books about Birth Control Population Limitation, 8 Related Subjects," undated (Box 91, Folder 88)
  - "Birth Control: A Balance Sheet," Reprint from Forum and Century 1932 (Box 91, Folder 89)
  - "Birth Control: New York's Untold Story," New York Post Reprint 1957 (Box 91, Folder 90)
  - "Birth Control By Pill," William H. White, Reprint, Look 1952 (Box 91, Folder 91)
  - "Birth Control Centers," 1936 (Box 91, Folder 92)
  - "The Birth Control Crusade Marches On," Margaret Sanger 1936 (Box 91, Folder 93)
  - "Birth Control and Civil Liberties, 1916-1941," 1944 (Box 91, Folder 94)
  - "Birth Control: The Case for the State," Don Wharton, Reprint, Reader's Digest 1939 (Box 91, Folder 95)
  - "Birth Control for Teenagers," Reprint, Sexual Behavior, Feb. 1972 (Box 91, Folder 96)
  - "Birth Control Information on Campus," Reprint, National Reporter, ZPG by College Program, PPWP 1971 (Box 91, Folder 97)
  - "Birth Control in the Courts," 1942 (Box 91, Folder 98)
  - "World Birth Control Challenge," by Robert Coughlan, Life, 11/23/59 (Box 91, Folder 99)
  - "Birth Control: The Doctors Duty," Sanger, Margaret, 6/37 (Box 91, Folder 100)
  - "Birth Control and Depression," Bromley, Harpers 1934 (Box 91, Folder 101)
  - "Birth Control for More Negro Babies," Dr. E. Franklin Frazier, undated (Box 91, Folder 102)
  - "Birth control is Accepted by American Medical Association," 1937 (Box 91, Folder 103)
  - The Nation, "Sanctified Birth Control," By Dorothy Dunbar Bromley 1934 (Box 91, Folder 104)
  - "Birth Control and the Christian," By Irene Soehren, Reprint, Christian Herald 1959 (Box 91, Folder 105)
  - Birth Control: Letter By General Eisenhower, Reprint, 6/23/65 (Box 91, Folder 106)
  - Birth Control: Latin-American Catholics, Reprint from Look, July 14, 1964 (Box 91, Folder 107)
  - Birth Control Education, Reprint, N.Y. Herald Tribune, 3/19/65 1965 (Box 91, Folder 108a)
  - "Birth Control and the Lower Class, Unmarried Mother," By Sidney Furie, Reprint from Social Work 1966, [MISSING] (Box 91, Folder 108b)
  - Birth Control on Medical Opinion 1938 (Box 91, Folder 109)
  - "Birth Control and the Moral Law," 1930 (Box 91, Folder 110)
  - Birth Control, New Day Dawns 1937 (Box 91, Folder 111)
  - "Birth Control, New Style," 1947 (Box 91, Folder 112)
  - "B.C. In the No. Carolina Health Dept.," Cooper, G.M., Dr. 1940 (Box 91, Folder 113)
  - "A Birth Control Pioneer Among Migrants," Condensed, Survey Graphic, Reprint, Readers Digest 1943 (Box 91, Folder 114)
  - "Birth Control: A Practical Survey," Stone, Hannah M., M.D. 1937-1938 (Box 91, Folder 115)
  - "Birth Control: A Present Day Survey," Stone, Hannah M., M.D., 1941, Revised 1937-1945 (Box 91, Folder 116)
  - Birth Control and Public Health, Dr. C.E.A. Winslow, 1934, Revised 1939 (Box 91, Folder 117)
  - "Birth Control: Public Controversy, Private Acceptance," Reprint, N.Y. Tribune, 3/16/65 (Box 91, Folder 118)
  - "This Question of Birth Control," Bromley, Harpers 1929 (Box 91, Folder 119)
  - Birth Control, Reprint, Los Angeles Times, PP Los Angeles 1964 (Box 91, Folder 120)
  - Birth Control: Reprint, Seminar, Corpus Christi, Texas 7/14/65 (Box 91, Folder 121)
  - "Birth Control Revolution," by S.M. Spencer, Reprint, Saturday Evening Post 1966 (Box 91, Folder 122)
  - "Birth Control in a State Public Health Program," 1938 (Box 91, Folder 123)
  - Birth Control Services, Tax-Supported Hospitals, Economic Conference and Symposium 1963 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Birth Control Research Bureau, Flyer 1937 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - "The Birth Control Raid," Stone, Hannah M., M.D., Reprint, Eugenics, August 1929 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - "Birth Control: Questions and Answers," 1939 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Birth Control and Public Relief, by Bossard, James H. 1934 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Birth Control Pill, Spanish Versions, Questions and Answers 1962 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - "Birth Control Services in Tax-Supported Institutions," San Francisco Workshop Digest 1962 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - "Birth Control to Millions," Reprint, Medical World News, Dr. A.F. Guttmacher, 10/21/66 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - "Birth Control Service Among Urban Negroes," Drs. Overton and Uffelman, Reprint, Human Fertility 1942 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - "Birth Control: Success Story No. 1," By Arthur Gordon, Reprint, Reader's Digest, Jan. 1970 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Birth Control, by Ernest Havermann and Editors of Time-Life Books, Introduction by Dr. A.F. Guttmacher 1967 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - "Birth Control: The Problem We Fear to Face," 1961 (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - Birth Control: Study Outline 1936-1938 (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - "Birth Control Taboos are Easing," Harold Schmeck, N.Y. Times Reprint, Nov. 18, 1962 (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - "Birth Control Through the Ages," By Sanger, Margaret 1940Reprint Revised, 1942 (Box 92, Folder 15)
  - Birth Control: Its Sue [sic] and Misuse, Abstract, Bromley 1935 (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - "Birth Control U.S.A.," 1952 (Box 92, Folder 17)
  - "Birth Control, U.S. Programs Off to Slow Start," Elinor Langer, Reprint, Science, May 12, 1967 (Box 92, Folder 18)
  - "Birth Control and the War on Poverty," Reprint, N.Y. Post, Dec. 14, 1964 (Box 92, Folder 19)
  - White House Conference on Int'l Cooperation, 11/65 Rpt. Population, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 20)
  - Birth Control, "We Can End the Battle Over Birth Control," John Rock, Good Housekeeping 1961 (Box 92, Folder 21)
  - "Birth Control Debated at White House Forum," 1965 Reprint, N.Y. Herald Tribune, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 22)
  - "Birth Control, Where do We Stand Today?," Reprint from Pageant 1952 (Box 92, Folder 23)
  - "Birth Rate and Birth Right," By Marian Maury 1963 (Box 92, Folder 24)
  - Birth Specter, Reprint, Newsweek, 2/9/48 (Box 92, Folder 25)
  - Blueprint for Happiness Campaign 1951 (Box 92, Folder 26)
  - Books: Selected Bibliography of Professionals on Family Planning, May 1964 (Box 92, Folder 27)
  - Board Member Soul Searching, Survey, Midmonthly, Reprint, March 1938 (Box 92, Folder 28)
  - "Breaking the Viscous Cycle," 1954 (Box 92, Folder 29)
  - Briefs: B.C. Situation, Conn., Oct. Term 1964, 1980 (Box 92, Folder 30)
  - Brief Guide for Campaign Speakers, Campaign 1947 (Box 92, Folder 31)
  - Briefs: Legal, Conn., October Term 1964 (Box 92, Folder 32)
  - Briefs: State of Connecticut 1960 (Box 92, Folder 33)
  - Books About Birth Control and Related Subjects 1960 (Box 92, Folder 34)
  - Books About Birth Control, Population Limitations and Other Subjects 1963 (Box 92, Folder 35)
  - Books About Population and Family and Related Subjects 1966-1968 (Box 92, Folder 36)
  - Books on Planned Parenthood 1951 (Box 92, Folder 37)
  - Booklists 1935-1947 (Box 92, Folder 38)
  - "Boy Meets Girl in Wartime," Amer. Social Hygiene 1943 (Box 92, Folder 39)
  - The Bulletin 1940-1941 (Box 92, Folder 40)
  - "By Choice," 1953 Campaign (Box 92, Folder 41)
  - Campaign Sales 1955 (Box 92, Folder 42)
  - Campaigns That Click Issue, #1 Affiliates, Fund Raising Bulletin 1955 (Box 92, Folder 43)
  - Can Wider Distribution of P.P. Information Decrease the Third Largest Group of Deaths in U.S.? 1948 (Box 92, Folder 44)
  - "The Case for Birth Control," undated (Box 92, Folder 45)
  - "Case for Planned Parenthood in Massachusetts," 1947 (Box 92, Folder 46)
  - "Case of Simple Arithmetic," Campaign 1952 (Box 92, Folder 47)
  - "Case for the Small Family," By Winfield Best, Reprint, Parents Magazine, June 1966 (Box 92, Folder 48)
  - A Case Study Series: "Sexual Health Programs Involving Youth," Reprint, Youth and Student Affairs, PPFA 1976 (Box 92, Folder 49)
  - Casemaker, The Client and Family Planning, 4/68 (Box 92, Folder 50)
  - "The Case for Small Families," E.J. Lieberman, Reprint, New York Times Magazine, 3/70 (Box 92, Folder 51)
  - "Case Work Treatment of Emotional Maladjustment in Marriage," Reprint, The Family, December 1944 (Box 92, Folder 52)
  - "The Case Worker and Family Planning," 2nd Printing, undated (Box 92, Folder 53)
  - "Case Worker, the Client and Family Planning," By Helen P. Stanford, 4/68 (Box 92, Folder 54)
  - "The Case Worker, the Client, and Family Planning," By Helen Stanford 1971 (Box 92, Folder 55)
  - The Case Workers' Role, by E.V. Merril, Paper Read at N.C.S.W. 1949 (Box 92, Folder 56)
  - Catalog of Services 1941 (Box 92, Folder 57)
  - "Catholics Take a New Look at Pill," By Jack Star, Reprinted from Sept. 8, 1964, Look Magazine, 1964 (Box 92, Folder 58)
  - "Catholics and Birth Control," by George Barrett, August 1963, New York Times Reprint, 1963 (Box 92, Folder 59)
  - "Catholicism Fights Birth Control," By C.P. Trowbridge, Rev., Reprint, New Republic 1945 (Box 92, Folder 60)
  - Catholics and Birth Control, Bromley Write Up, New York World Telegram, Dec. 1935 (Box 92, Folder 61)
  - "Catholics on Birth Control," By Guy Irving Burch, Reprint, New Republic 1934 (Box 92, Folder 62)
  - Catholics and Planned Parenthood, By J.H.J. Upham, M.D., Reprint, American Mercury, Feb. 1944 (Box 92, Folder 63)
  - "Catholics and Birth Control," Campaign of Boycott and Villification, Reprint, The Churchman, April 1941 (Box 92, Folder 64)
  - "Catholics and Birth Control," Flagrant Threats Against the Press, Reprint, The Churchman, May 1941 (Box 92, Folder 65)
  - "The Challenge of Birth Control," Himes; "The Need for Birth Control," Everett 1938 (Box 92, Folder 66)
  - "Challenge of Today, Heroism of Yesterday," 50th Anniv. Film 1966 (Box 92, Folder 67)
  - "Changes of the Consistency of Contraceptive Preparations During Storage," By Royal L. Brown, M.D., Reprint, Human Fertility, Dec. 1942 (Box 92, Folder 68)
  - "Changing Attitudes Toward the Mass. Birth Control Law," Joseph L. Dorsey, M.D., Reprint, New England Journal of Medicine 1964 (Box 92, Folder 69)
  - "Childbearing Aspirations of Public Health Maternity Patients," Robt. H. Browning, MPH and L.I. Parks M.P.H., Nov. 1964 (Box 92, Folder 70)
  - "Child Spacing," By Frederick C. Holden, M.D., Out of Print 1931, 1938 (Box 92, Folder 71)
  - "Child Spacing and Family Economic Position," Ronald Freedman and L. Coombs, Reprint, American Sociological Review 1966 (Box 92, Folder 72)
  - Children by Choice, Facts Leaflet, Campaign 1943 (Box 92, Folder 73)
  - Children of the World Deserve to be Planned 1964 (Box 92, Folder 74)
  - Churches Speak Up, On Birth Control 1960-1968 (Box 92, Folder 75)
  - Civil Liberties, "A Right is Born," by Harriet F. Pilpel 1965 (Box 92, Folder 76)
  - City Bank of Family Health Campaign, New York City 1949 (Box 92, Folder 77)
  - Christmas card, undated (Box 92, Folder 78)
  - Christian Examines Planned Parenthood, Presbyterian Survey, by Kathleen Cabell 1965 (Box 92, Folder 79)
  - Clergymen's Replies: Ethics of B.C., Replies to Cardinal Hayes 1935 (Box 92, Folder 80)
  - Clinic Forms 1958-1967 (Box 92, Folder 81)
  - Clinical Contraceptive Results, Council on Pharmacy and Chemistry, By G.W. Beebe and C.J. Gamble, M.D. 1940 (Box 92, Folder 82)
  - "Clinical Effectiveness of the Rhythm Method of Contraception," Tietz, Poliakoff, Rock 1951 (Box 92, Folder 83)
  - "Clinical Experience with a New Gel-Alone Method of Contraception," Reprinted, N.Y.A.S., May 1952 (Box 92, Folder 84)
  - "Closing the Gap," by George Lindsay, Approx. 1966, undated (Box 92, Folder 85)
  - "Come In," 1949 Campaign, New York City, 1949 (Box 92, Folder 86)
  - Community Action Program Guide, Office of Economic Opportunity, Washington D.C., Feb. 1965 (Box 92, Folder 87)
  - "Comparative Spermicidal Powers of 15 Commercial Contraceptives," By R.L. Brown and C.G. Gamble, Out of Print 1941 (Box 92, Folder 88)